A Guide to the Additional Rose Greely Papers, 1919 (1928-1956) 1960
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Additional Rose Greely Papers, 1919 (1928-1956) 1960
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10772-a
This collection consists of 670 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the library on 1991 December 9.
Biographical/Historical Information
Rose Greely was an American landscape architect.
Scope and Content Information
The collection contains client files and miscellaneous papers and photographs.
Client files consist chiefly of photographs of her landscape designs with occasional related blueprints, sketches, photostats or newsclippings.
Miscellaneous papers include photographs of her cottage "Still Pond" in New Hampshire; correspondence pertaining to the photographs; a notebook and sketches of Spanish architectural styles; and illustrations for "Design in informal planting."
Contents List
- Alfaro, Mrs. Victor 1936-1937 (Box 1)
- Boy-Ed, Mrs. Karl - Berryville, Virginia ("Callander") 1940-1942, n.d. (Box 1)
- Burling, Mrs. Edward - Washington, D.C. 1932, n.d. (Box 1)
- Cafritz, Morris - Washington, D.C. 1937 (Box 1)
- Cross, Whitman - Chevy Chase, Maryland 1928, n.d. (Box 1)
- [Folger, Mrs. J. Clifford ?] - Washington, D.C. n.d. (Box 1)
- Hahm, Miss Emma T. - Washington, D.C. 1932-1940, n.d. (Box 1)
- Hill, Mr. & Mrs. William Hurd - Washington, D.C. ca. 1943 (Box 1)
- Houghton, A.B. - Washington, D.C. 1934, n.d. (Box 1)
- Lansing, Mrs. C.C. - Salisbury, Connecticut 1928, n.d. (Box 1)
- McQuade, Victor - Millbrook, New York 1928, n.d. (Box 1)
- Murray, Mrs. Lewis N. - Dunkirk, New York ("Dunkeld") n.d. (Box 1)
- Peter, Mr. & Mrs. Walter 1958 (Box 1)
- Putzki, Dr. Paul S. - Washington, D.C. 1933-1937, 1956, n.d., 2 folders (Box 2)
- Simms, Mrs. Albert G. - Washington, D.C. 1929-1932 (Box 2)
- Sortwell, Mrs. Frances - Georgetown 1934, n.d. (Box 2)
- Taylor, William - Washington, D.C. 1937-1942, n.d. (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous Papers 1943-1959 (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous Photographs 1938-1948, n.d. (Box 2)
- Notebook re Spanish Architecture with Sketches n.d. (Box 2)
- Blueprints entitled "Redly Plan # 2" n.d., 2 items (Folder 1)
- Photostats of architectural drawings by Rose Greely to illustrate her Thesis in the School of Domestic & Landscape Architecture, Cambridge, Massachusetts 1919, 24 items (Folder 1)
- Landscape Photographs of Mrs. J. Clifford Folger, Mrs. Samuel Swartz, Mrs. Gilbert Hitchcock, and Kenyon Bolton 1936, 1951, n.d., 17 items (Folder 1)
- Blueprints for Mr. & Mrs. Henry S. Huidekoper, Loughboro Road & Millwood Lane, include a terrace planting plan, construction plan, Loughboro Road survey and a general planting plan 1959-1960, 17 items (Folder 2)
- Blueprints for Mr. & Mrs. Walter Peter, study for planting n.d., 2 items (Folder 2)